Guide to the Russian portraits: photograph album, 1865
Department of Special Collections
Russian portraits: photograph album,
1865
Special Collections Mss Photo 401
Tarsaidze, Alexandre, 1899-1978
1 v. (144 photoprints)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Alexandre G. Tarsaidze, 1979.
Biography
The collector, Alexandre Tarsaidze (1899-1978), was the author of several books on the history of Russia before the Revolution, all published in New York.
Scope and Content
Portraits of royalty, heads of state, military leaders, religious leaders, scientists, writers, actors, artists, dancers and aboriginal peoples.
AL'BOM FOTOGRAFICHESKIKH PORTRETOV
- Gosudar' Nasliednik Tsesarevich Nikolai Aleksandrovich. Nikolai Aleksandrovich, grand duke of Russia, 1843-1865(eldest son of Alexander II), Print No. 1.
- Vysokonarechennaia neviesta Gosud. Nasl. Tses.: Mariia Printsessa Datskaia. Mariia Fedorovna, consort of Alexander III, Emperor of Russia, 1847-1928, 2.
- E.I.V. Velikii Kniaz' Vladimir Aleksandrovich. Vladimir Aleksandrovich, grand duke of Rusia 1847-1909(son of Alexander II), 3.
- E.I.V. Velikii Kniaz' Aleksii Aleksandrovich. Aleksei Aleksandrovich, Grand duke of Russia (son of Alexander II), Chief of the Imperial Navy, 1850-1908, 4.
- E.I.V. Velikaia Kniazhna Mariia Aleksandrovna. Mariia Aleksandrovna, grand duchess of Russia (daughter to Alexander II) 1853-1920, 5.
- E.I.V. Velikii Kniaz' Sergii Aleksandrovich. Sergei Aleksandrovich, grand duke of Russia (son of Alexander II) Governor of Moscow 1857-1905, 6.
- E.V. Velikii Kniaz' Pavel Aleksandrovich. Pavel Aleksandrovich (son of Alexander II) 1860-1919, 7.
- E.Imp.Vys.Vel.Kn. Konstantin Nikolaevich. Konstantin Nikolaevich, grand duke of Russia, 1827-1892.(son of Nicholas I), 8.
- E.V. Velikaia Kniazhna Ol'ga Konstantinovna. Ol'ga Konstantinovna, grand-duchess of Russia, Consort of King George I of Greece., 9.
- Ego Imp. Vysoch. Velikii Kniaz' Nikolai Konstantinovich. Nikolai Konstantinovich, grand duke of Russia, 1850-1918?, 10.
- Ego Imp. Vysoch. Vilikii Kniaz' Konstantin Konstantinovich. Konstantin Konstantinovioh, grand duke of Russia, 1858-1915.Poet, known under pseud, K.R., 11.
- E.V. Velikii Kniaz' Mikhail Nikolaevich. Mikhail Nikolaevich, grand duke of Russia, 1832-1909,General Governor of Caucasia (son of Nicholas I), 12.
- E.I.V. Velik. Kn. Nikolai Nikolaevich. Nikolai Nikolaevich, grand duke of Russia, 1831-1891.Commander-in-Chief of the Russian Army during the war with Turkey, 1877.(son of Nicholas I), 13.
- E.V. Velikaia Kniaginia Ol'ga Fedorovna. Ol'ga Fedorovna, grand duchess of Russia, 1839-1891.Born Cecilia, Princess of Baden., 14.
- Gertsog Osuna-i-Infantado, Ispanskii posol pri Dvorie Ego Velichestva. Spanish ambassador at the Imperial Court., 15.
- Svietl. Kniaz' V.D. Golitsyn, nachal'n. l-i Gvard. Kaval. Devizii, 16.
- Svietl. Kniaz' E.L. Vitgenshtein, Svity Ego Velich. General-Maior., 17.
- Kniaz' A.I. Bariatinskii, Komand. L.-Gb. Preobrazh. polka., 18.
- Kniaz' V.I. Bariatinskii, komandir Kavalergardskago polka., 19.
- Kniaz' D.O. Bebutov, general-leitenant., 20.
- Kniaz' P.P. Gagarin., 21.
- Kniaz' A.M. Gorchakov, Vitse-kantsler, Ministr Inostrannykh Diel. Kniaz' A.M. Gorchakov, Vice-Canceleor, Minister of the Interior (in 1865), 22.
- Kniaz' V.A. Dolgorukov 1, Shef korpusa zhandarm., General ot kavalerii., 23.
- Graf F.V. Orlov-Denisov, Gener.-Adiut. (skonchavshiisia), 24.
- Graf F.F. Berg, Namiestnik E. Imp. Vel. v Tsarstvie Pol'skim (ponegativu iz Varshavy), 25.
- Graf A.V. Adlerberg 2-i, Komand. Glavn. Kvart., Gener.-Adiutant, Gener.-Leiten., 26.
- Graf V.F. Adlerberg, Ministr Imper. Dvora. Graf V.F. Adlerberg, Minister of the Imperial Court (in 1865), 27.
- Graf Eduard Trof. Baranox, General-Leitenant., 28.
- Graf B.A. Perovskii, General-Adiutant., 29.
- Graf N.T. Baranov l-i, Gener.-Adiutant, Gener.-Leitenant., 30.
- G.Kh. Gasfort, Gener. ot Infant., Chlen Gosud. Sovieta., 31.
- F.S. Paniutin, Gener.-Adiut., Chlen Gosud. Sovieta (skonchavshiisia), 32.
- A.I. Panfilov, Vitse-Admiral., 33.
- M.G. Khomutov, General ot Kavalerii, Khomutov byvshii Nakazn. Ataman Voiska Donskago (skonchavshiisia), 34.
- Baron E.F. Meiendorf, Gener.-Ad#iut., Gener. ot Kavalerii., 35.
- A.A. Barantsov l-i, Tovarishch General-Feld'dtseikhmeistera, Gener.-AD'iut., General-Leitenant., 36.
- L.I. Gergard, General-Maior, Direktor Telegrafov., 37.
- P.A. Dubovitskii. Prezident Mediko-Khirurgicheskoi Akademii., 38.
- P.P. Mel'nikov, Gener.-Leit., Glavno-Upravliaiushchii Putiami Soobshcheniia., 39.
- V.F. Von der Launits, General-Adiutant (skonchavshiisia), 40.
- P.A. Kolzakov, Gener.-Adiut., Admiral (skonchavshiisia), 41.
- Svietl. Kn. Italiiskii Graf A.A. Suvorov-Rymnikskii., 42.
- Graf N.I. Evdokimov., 43.
- F.P. Litke, General Adiutant. Admiral. Prezid. Imper. Akad. Nauk. F.P. Litke. President of the Imperial Academy of Sciences (in 1865), 44.
- A.O. Diugamel', Komand. voisk. v Zapadn. Sibiri, Gen. ot inf., 45.
- Graf A.N. Liders, Gener.-Adiut., Gener. ot Infant., 46.
- P. Kh. Grabbe l., Nakaznyi Ataman Voiska Donskago., 47.
- A.F. Minkvits, Nachal'nik Shtaba Varshav. Voen. okruga, Gener.-Adiut., 48.
- A.P. Bazak, Kievskii Voennyi Gener.-Gubernator. A.P. Bazak, Military general-governor of Kiev (in 1865), 49.
- G.G. Vilamov, Gener.-Leitenant., 50.
- N.K. Krabbe, Upravliaiushchii Morskim Ministerstvom., 51.
- A.I. Ushakov, Gener. ot Infanterii., 52.
- B.G. Glinka, Gener.-Adiut., Gener.-Leitenant., 53.
- IA.P. Baklanov, General-Leitenant, 54.
- P.V. Kozakevich, Kontr-Admiral., 55.
- K.N. Pos'et, Svity Ego Velich. kontr-Admiral, 56.
- A.N. Sutgov. General-Leitenant., 57.
- F.S. Tsytsurin. Pochetn. Leib-Medik, Direktor Voen.-Medits. Departamenta., 58.
- N.O. Sukhozanet, Gener.-Adiut., Gener. ot Artillerii., 59.
- A.E. Timashev, Gener.-Adiut., Gener.-Leiten., 60.
- Baron A.K. von Tetenborn, Svity E. Velichestva Gener.-Maior., 61.
- A.I. Butakov 2-i, Sv. E. Velich. Kontr-Admiral., 62.
- A.I. Filosofov, Generl.-ADiut., General ot Artillerii., 63.
- A.P. Akhmatov, General-Adiutant, General-Leitenant., 64.
- S.A. Khrulev, General-Leitenant., 65.
- S.D. Bezobrazov 1-i, Gener.-Adiut., General ot Kavalerii., 66.
- E.V. Brimmer, General-Leitenant., 67.
- Kniaz' P.A. Viazemskii., 68.
- Kniaz' D.A. Obolenskii. Stats-Sekretar', Tainyi Sovetnik., 69.
- Graf P.P. Shuvalov, Kamerger Dvora Ego Velichestva., 70.
- P.A. Valuev, Ministr Vnutr. Diel. P.A. Valuev, Minister of the Interior (in 1865), 71.
- Graf S.S. Lanskoi, byvshii Ministr Vnutr. Diel (skonchavsh.), 72.
- A.G. Troinitskii, Tainyi Sovietn., tovarishch Min. Vn. Diel., 73.
- M.Kh. Reitern, Ministr Finansov. M.Kh. Reitern, Finance Minister (in 1865), 74.
- Baron A.L. Shtiglits, Tain. Sov., Direktor Gosud. Banka. Baron A.L. Shtiglits, Director of State Bank (in 1865), 75.
- A.S. Norov, Diestv. Tain. Gov., Chl. Gosud. Sovieta, 76.
- Graf A.M. Borkh, Direktor Imp. Teatrov. Graf A.M. Borkh, Director of Imperial Theaters, 77.
- Graf A.P. Shuvalov, Ober-Gofmarshal., 78.
- F.I. Prianishnikov, Diestv. Tain. Sov., Chlen Gos. Sov., 79.
- A.M. Kniazhevich, Dieistv. Tain. Sov., Chlen Gosud. Sov., 80.
- K.A. Ton, Rektor Imp. Akad. Khudozh. po chasti Arkhitektury., 81.
- F.I. Tiutchev, Kamerger Dvora E. Imp. Velichestva., 82.
- N.A. Miliutin, Stats-Sekretar', Tain. Sov., 83.
- KK. Grot, Stats-Sekretar', Tainyi Sovietn., 84.
- P.K. Meiendorf, Ober-Gofmeister Dvora Ego Velichestva (skonchavshiisia), 85.
- N.A. Gerngros, Tain. Sov., Tov. Ministra Gosud. Imush., 86.
- P.G. Riedkin, Byvshii Prof. Moskovsk. Universiteta, Tainyi Sovietnik., 87.
- V.V. Pelikan, Sovieshch. Chl. Med. Sovieta, Tainyi Sovietn., 88.
- P.A. Morits, Sekretar' Eia Velichestva., 89.
- P.L. Chebyshev, Chl. Uchen. Komiteta, Dieistv. St. Sov., 90.
- M.S. Kutorga, Akademik, Dieistv. St. Sov. Kutorga, Mikhail Semenovich, 1809-, 91.
- K.M. Ber, Akademik. Baer, Karl Ernst von, 1792-1876., 92.
- N.F. Zdekauer, Leib-Medik, Professor., 93.
- A.N. Nikitenko, Ord. Akademik Imp.Akad. Nauk., 94.
- Stasiulevich, Professor., 95.
- Botkin. Professor Mediko-Khirurg. Akademii., 96.
- I.K. Aivazovskii, Professor morskoi zhivopisi. Aivazovskii, Ivan Konstantinovich, 1817-1900., 97.
- V.E. Ekk, Professor Imp. Medike-Khirurgich. Akad., 98.
- D.I. Grimm, Professor Arkhitektury., 99.
- F.I. Iordan, Professor Gravirovaniia., 100.
- F.A. Bruni, Rektor Imp. Akademii Khudozhestv. Bruni, Fedor Antonovich, 1800-1875.Director of Imp. Akademiia Khudozhestv., 101.
- N.I. Grech, Russkii Pisatel', rod. 1787.Grech, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1787-1867, 102.
- Lomonosov, Russkii Pisatel'. Lomonosov, Mikhail Vasil'evich, 1711-1765., 103.
- V.G. Benediktov, Poet. Benediktov, Vladimir Grigor'evich, 1807-1873., 104.
- N.V. Kukol'nik, Pisatel'. Kukol'nik, Nestor Vasil'evich. 1809-1868., 105.
- I.S. Turgenev, Literator. Turgenev, Ivan Sergeevich, 1818-1883., 106.
- N.A. Nekrasov. Nekrasov, Nikolai Alekseevich, 1821-1877., 107.
- V.F. Korsh, Redaktor i Izdatel' S.-Peterb. Viedomostei. Korsh, Valentin Fedorovich, 1828-1883,ed., 108.
- N.V. Gerbel', izdatel' sochinenii Shillera v perevodie na Russkii iazyk., 109.
- V.S. Kurochkin, Izdatel' iskry. Kurochkin, Vasilii Stepanovich, 1831-1875,ed., 110.
- A.A. Kraevskii, Redaktor gazety Golos. Kraevskii, Andrei Aleksandrovich, 1810-1889,ed., 111.
- Grafina M.G. Razumovskaia, Davalerstv. Dama (skonchavshaiasia)., 112.
- E.V. Rodzianko, Nachal'n. Uch. Ord. Sv. Ekateriny, Kavalerstven. Dama., 113.
- Isidor, Mitropolit Novgorodskii, S.-Peterburg-skii, Estlandskii i Finliandskii., 114.
- Mitropolit Kievskii i Galitskii Arsenii., 115.
- V. B. Bazhanov, Kukhovnik Ikh Imp. Velich. i Vysoch., 116.
- Platon, Arkhiepiskop Rizhskii i Mitavskii., 117.
- Sofoniia, Episkop Novomirgorodskii., 118.
- Ioann, Episkop Poltavskii i Pereiaslavskii., 119.
- Arkhimandrit Vladimir. Inspektor S.-Peterb. Dukhovnoi Akademii., 120.
- V.A. Karatygin, Artist Imperat. Teatr. (skonchavshiisia), 121.
- A. M. Karatygina, byvshaia Artistka Imp. Teatr., 122.
- A.E. Martynov, Artist Imp. teatr. (skonchavshiisia), 123.
- I.I. Sosnitskii, Artist Imper. Teatrov (v roli Gorodnichago v Revizorie), 124.
- Taska, Artist Italianskoi opery Imperat. Teatrov., 125.
- I.F. Gorbunov, Artist Imp. Teatr. (stsena iz Narodnago byta), 126.
- F.A. Burdin, Artist Imp. Teatr. (v roli L'va Krasnova, v dr. Griekh da bieda na kogo ne zhivet), 127.
- V.V. Samoilov, Artist Imp. Teatrov., 128.
- F.A. Snietkova, Dramat. artistka Imp. Teatrov. (Ostaviv. stsenu)., 129.
- Deveriia, Artistka Imp. Teatr. frantsuzskoi stseny., 130.
- L.P. Radina 1-ia, Baletnaia Artistka Imp. Teatrov., 131.
- V.P. Radina 2-ia, Baletna ia Artistka Imp. Teatrov., 132.
- O. P. Radina 3 i-a, Baletn. Artistka Imp. Teatrov., 133.
- A.D. Kosheva, Baletn. Artistka Imp. Teatrov., 134.
- M.N. Madaeva, Baletnaia artistka Imp. Teatr., 135.
- G-zha Kemmerer, Baletnaia artistka Imp. Teatr., 136.
- M.S. Petipa, Baletn. artistka Imp. teatrov., 137.
- V.I. Lapshina, Baletn. Artistka Imp. Teatr., 138.
- Stefanskaia, Baletnaia artistka Varshavskago teatra (fotografiia G-na Faiansa v Varshavie., 139.
- N.N. Amosova 2-ia, Baletn. artistka Imper. Teatrov., 140.
- Tipy: Samoiedy., 141.
- Tipy Mach'ku, iz primorskago Kraia Amurskoi oblasti., 142.
- Tipy: Malorossiianin., 143.
- Ken'ma, Negedalets ili Zhzhy., 144.